var flashcards = 
    {
"Unit 7":
[
    {
        "answer": "number\n", 
        "question": "Stem: numer\n\nExamples: enumerate, numeral, numerous, supernumeraries, numerology\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "strong\n", 
        "question": "Stem: fort\n\nExamples: fortitude, fort, fortify, fortification, comfort, forte, fortissimo, pianoforte\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "bone\n", 
        "question": "Stem: osteo\n\nExamples: osteopath, osteology, osteopathy, osteoblast, osteocyte, osteotomy\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "bird\n", 
        "question": "Stem: ornith\n\nExamples: ornithology, ornithologist, ornithopter, ornithomancy, ornithosis\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "city\n", 
        "question": "Stem: polis\n\nExamples: metropolis, megalopolis, police, polite, policy, acropolis, necropolis\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "pour\n", 
        "question": "Stem: fus\n\nExamples: transfusion, infusion, refuse, fusillade, fusion, infuse, confusion\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "I\n", 
        "question": "Stem: ego\n\nExamples: egomaniac, egocentric, egotistical, egotist, egotize, egoism, alter ego\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "breathe\n", 
        "question": "Stem: spir\n\nExamples: inspire, respiration, perspiration, expire, spirit, aspire, conspire\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "across\n", 
        "question": "Stem: dia\n\nExamples: diagonal, diameter, dialogue, dialect, diatribe, diaphanous, dialectic\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "sharp\n", 
        "question": "Stem: acr\n\nExamples: acrimonious, acerbity, acrid, acridine, acrimony, acerate\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "high, point or tip\n", 
        "question": "Stem: acro\n\nExamples: acrobrat, acronym, acropolis, acrophobia, acromegaly, acrocarpous\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "blame\n", 
        "question": "Stem: culp\n\nExamples: culprit, culpable, exculpate, inculpate, exculpatory\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "skin\n", 
        "question": "Stem: derm\n\nExamples: dermatologist, dermatitis, pachyderm, hypodermic, ectoderm, endoderm\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "animal\n", 
        "question": "Stem: zo\n\nExamples: zoo, protozoa, zoophilous, zooplankton, zoophagous, Mesozoic, zodiac\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "through\n", 
        "question": "Stem: per\n\nExamples: perception, perforation, percolate, perambulate, peregrination\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "peace\n", 
        "question": "Stem: pac\n\nExamples: pacify, pacific, pacifist, pacifier, pacifism, Pax Romana, pacification\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "short\n", 
        "question": "Stem: brev\n\nExamples: brevity, abbreviation, breve, breviary, brief\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "death\n", 
        "question": "Stem: necro\n\nExamples: necropolis, necromancer, necrophobia, necrotic, necrobiosis\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "city\n", 
        "question": "Stem: urb\n\nExamples: urban, urbane, suburbs, urbanite, urbanologist, urbanism\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "fight\n", 
        "question": "Stem: pugn\n\nExamples: pugnacious, repugnant, pugilist, impugn, oppugn, inexpugnable\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "outer\n", 
        "question": "Stem: ecto\n\nExamples: ectoderm, ectozoa, ectomorph, ectothermic, ectoplasm, ectoparasite\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "molded\n", 
        "question": "Stem: plasto\n\nExamples: plastic, dermoplasty, rhinoplasty, plater, plasticity, plastid\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "leader\n", 
        "question": "Stem: agog\n\nExamples: demagogue, pedagogue, synagogue, agogics, pedagogy, mystatgogue\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "small\n", 
        "question": "Stem: cle\n\nExamples: molecule, corpuscle, follicle, minuscule, ventricle, particle, vesicle\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "not\n", 
        "question": "Stem: il\n\nExamples: illegal, illiterate, illicit, illogical, illegible, illiberal\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }
],
"Lesson 18":
[
    {
        "answer": "belittle", 
        "question": "To make a person or thing seem unimportant or without value\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "envelop", 
        "question": "To wrap within; to surround entirely\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "exploit", 
        "question": "a.  To use to the greatest possible advantage\nb.  To make use of selfishly and unfairly\nc.  An exciting or a heroic adventure or deed\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "facilitate", 
        "question": "To make easier or to help along; to assist\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "forsake", 
        "question": "To make worse; to damage\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "impair", 
        "question": "To change or adjust; to alter\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "inflict", 
        "question": "To cause pain; to do something unpleasant or punishing\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "inhumane", 
        "question": "Brutal; cruel; lacking kindness and pity\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "rehabilitate", 
        "question": "To restore to a healthy or good condition\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "rejuvenate", 
        "question": "To make young or vigorous again\n"
    }
],
"Lesson 17":
[
    {
        "answer": "agile", 
        "question": "a.  Able to move quickly and easily\nb.  Mentally alert; sharp\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "dawdle", 
        "question": "To take more time than necessary; to move slowly\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "distort", 
        "question": "a.  To change something so as to make it less true; to misrepresent\nb.  To twist out of the usual shape\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "itinerary", 
        "question": "The route for a journey\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "mobilize", 
        "question": "a.  To prepare or to organize for a purpose\nb.  To prepare for a fight or for war\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "modify", 
        "question": "To change or adjust; to alter\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "quiver", 
        "question": "To tremble or shake\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "recede", 
        "question": "To go back; to retreat; to move away\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "supplant", 
        "question": "To replace\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "traverse", 
        "question": "To travel or pass across; over, or through\n"
    }
],
"Unit 6":
[
    {
        "answer": "vital or related\n", 
        "question": "Stem: germ\n\nExamples: germane, germinate, germicide, germinal, germ\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "group\n", 
        "question": "Stem: greg\n\nExamples: gregarious, egregious, gregariously, segregate, congregate, aggregate\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "sea\n", 
        "question": "Stem: mar\n\nExamples: marine, marina, ultramarine, maritime, mariner, marinate, submarine\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "first\n", 
        "question": "Stem: prim\n\nExamples: prime, primary, primate, primogeniture, primeval, prima donna, primo\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "fire\n", 
        "question": "Stem: pyro\n\nExamples: pyre, pyromania, pyrotechnic, pyrophobia, pyrometer\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "cry out\n", 
        "question": "Stem: clam\n\nExamples: clamorous, exclamation, clamor, exclamatory, clamant, declaim\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "more\n", 
        "question": "Stem: plu\n\nExamples: plural, plurality, plus, pluralize, pluriaxial, pluralism, nonplussed\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "touch\n", 
        "question": "Stem: tang\n\nExamples: tangible, tangent, tangle, tangential, cotangent, intangible\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "bind\n", 
        "question": "Stem: string\n\nExamples: stringent, stringy, astringent, stringer\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "free\n", 
        "question": "Stem: liber\n\nExamples: liberate, liberty, liberal, libertine, deliberate, libertarian\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "join\n", 
        "question": "Stem: junct\n\nExamples: junction, conjunction, juncture, disjunct, injunction, adjunct\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "close\n", 
        "question": "Stem: clud\n\nExamples: exclude, include, preclude, exclusive, occlude, conclude, cloister\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "light\n", 
        "question": "Stem: luc\n\nExamples: lucid, translucent, lucidity, pellucid, elucidate, lucent\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "spart\n", 
        "question": "Stem: se\n\nExamples: secede, secret, sedition, seduce, segregate, select, separate\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "pay\n", 
        "question": "Stem: trib\n\nExamples: tribute, tributary, retribution, contribution, attribute, diatribe, distribute\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "worthy\n", 
        "question": "Stem: dign\n\nExamples: dignify, dignity, condign, dignitary, undignified, indignation\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "break\n", 
        "question": "Stem: rupt\n\nExamples: erupt, disrupt, rupture, corrupt, abrupt, incorruptible\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "pleasing\n", 
        "question": "Stem: grat\n\nExamples: gratifying, gratitude, ingrate, grateful, gratuitous, ingratiate\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "middle\n", 
        "question": "Stem: medi\n\nExamples: median, mediate, medium, mediocre, Mediterranean\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "wisdom\n", 
        "question": "Stem: soph\n\nExamples: sophomore, sophisticated, sophist, philosophy, pansophy, theosophy\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "run\n", 
        "question": "Stem: curr\n\nExamples: current, undercurrent, currently, recurrent, currency, incur\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "time\n", 
        "question": "Stem: tempor\n\nExamples: temporal, contemporary, temporize, temporarily\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "wander\n", 
        "question": "Stem: migr\n\nExamples: migrate, transmigration, migrant, migratory, emigrant, immigrant\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "across\n", 
        "question": "Stem: trans\n\nExamples: transfer, translate, transmit, transfusion, translucent, transcend\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "marriage\n", 
        "question": "Stem: gamy\n\nExamples: monogamy, polygamy, bigamy, gamete, autogamous, exogamy\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }
],
"Lesson 16":
[
    {
        "answer": "chic", 
        "question": "Stylish, fashionable\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "debonair", 
        "question": "Charming in a friendly but sophisticated way\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "disheveled", 
        "question": "Messy; untidy in personal appearance\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "dowdy", 
        "question": "Having an old-fashioned appearance; shabby and out of style\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "drab", 
        "question": "Having a faded, dull appearance\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "garb", 
        "question": "a.  Clothing for a particular job or occasion\nb.  To dress in a particular way\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "ostentatious", 
        "question": "Showy; meant to impress others\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "rumple", 
        "question": "To wrinkle or crease\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "unsightly", 
        "question": "Unpleasant to look at\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "veneer", 
        "question": "a.  A thin, usually decorative layer of fine material glued onto an inferior material\nb.  An appearance giving a false, positive impression\n"
    }
],
"Lesson 15":
[
    {
        "answer": "alliance", 
        "question": "A close association or relationship based on shared needs or interest\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "collaborate", 
        "question": "a.  To work together on an intellectual or creative pursuit\nb.  To cooperate with an enemy invader\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "colleague", 
        "question": "A member of the same staff or profession; an associate\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "conspire", 
        "question": "TO plan together secretly\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "federation", 
        "question": "A formal association containing many individual groups or countries\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "harmonious", 
        "question": "Peaceful, pleasing, or appropriate when together or combined\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "interact", 
        "question": "To act on or affect each other\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "populace", 
        "question": "The general public; the population\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "unanimous", 
        "question": "In complete agreement; sharing the same opinion or view\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "uniform", 
        "question": "Always the same; not varying\n"
    }
],
        "Unit 5": [
    {
        "answer": "life\n", 
        "question": "Stem: vita\n\nExamples: vitamin, vitality, vital, revitalize, viable, vitalism, devitalize\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "people\n", 
        "question": "Stem: demo\n\nExamples: democracy, demography, undemocratic, democratize\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "solid\n", 
        "question": "Stem: stereo\n\nExamples: stereoscope, stereophonic, stereotype, stereopticon, stereotropism\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "doctrine\n", 
        "question": "Stem: ism\n\nExamples: Marxism, capitalism, Imagism, Cubism, nihilism, pluralism, tribalism\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "know\n", 
        "question": "Stem: cogn\n\nExamples: recognize, cognizant, incognito, cognoscenti, cognomen, precognition\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "over\n", 
        "question": "Stem: sur\n\nExamples: surplus, surpass, surcharge, surface, surfeit, surmount, surname, surtax\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "other\n", 
        "question": "Stem: alter\n\nExamples: alternator, alteration, alter ego, alternative, altruism, altercation\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "star\n", 
        "question": "Stem: astr\n\nExamples: astronomy, astrology, asteroid, disaster, asterisk, astrophysics, astrolabe\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "power\n", 
        "question": "Stem: dyna\n\nExamples: dynamic, dynamo, dynamite, dynasty, dynamometer\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "time\n", 
        "question": "Stem: chron\n\nExamples: chronometer, chronological, synchronize, chronic, anachronism\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "over\n", 
        "question": "Stem: hyper\n\nExamples: hyperactive, hyperventilate, hyperbole, hyperacidity, hypertension\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "moon\n", 
        "question": "Stem: luna\n\nExamples: lunar, lunatic, lunate, luna moth, lunette, sublunar, lunular\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "eight\n", 
        "question": "Stem: octa\n\nExamples: octameter, octogenarian, octagon, octarchy, octave, octopus, octahedron\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "turn\n", 
        "question": "Stem: gyro\n\nExamples: gyration, gyroscope, gyre, gyrate, spirogyra, gyromagnetic, gyrocomass\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "against\n", 
        "question": "Stem: contra\n\nExamples: contradict, contrary, contrast, contrapuntal, contraband, contravene\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "earth\n", 
        "question": "Stem: geo\n\nExamples: geography, geothermal, geology, geophysics, geometry, geosynchronous\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "sun\n", 
        "question": "Stem: helio\n\nExamples: Helios, heliotropic, heliocentric, heliograph, perihelion, aphelion\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "heat\n", 
        "question": "Stem: thermo\n\nExamples: thermostat, thermos, thermotropic, thermonuclear, thermocouple\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "four\n", 
        "question": "Stem: tetra\n\nExamples: tetrameter, tetrahedron, tetroxide, tetragon, tetrachloride, tetracycline\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "measure\n", 
        "question": "Stem: meter\n\nExamples: thermometer, millimeter, octometer, hydrometer, odometer\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "look\n", 
        "question": "Stem: scope\n\nExamples: telescope, microscope, periscope, radarscope, horoscope, electroscope\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "sound\n", 
        "question": "Stem: son\n\nExamples: sonar, unison, sonorous, sonnet, dissonance, resonant, supersonic\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "ten\n", 
        "question": "Stem: dec\n\nExamples: decade, decaliter, decimal, decagon, decathalon, decimate, dodecahedron\n\nOrigin: Greek\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "star\n", 
        "question": "Stem: stell\n\nExamples: interstellar, stelliform, stellar, constellation, stellate, stellify\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "love\n", 
        "question": "Stem: amat\n\nExamples: amatory, amateur, amorous, amigo, amiable, amity, amour\n\nOrigin: Latin\n\n"
    }
],
        "Lesson 12": [
    {
        "answer": "adage", 
        "question": "The traditional saying widely considered to wise and true\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "alliteration", 
        "question": "Repetition of sounds, usually of consonants, especially at the beginning of words\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "allusion", 
        "question": "An indirect reference to something\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "anthology", 
        "question": "A collections of writing by various authors\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "epic", 
        "question": "a.  A long poem or other literary work about heroes and their adventures\nb.  Grand or impressive in quality, size, or scope\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "hyperbole", 
        "question": "A extreme exaggeration\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "melodramatic", 
        "question": "Overly emotional or sentimental\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "personify", 
        "question": "a.  To represent an animal, object, or ideas as having human qualities\nb.  To be the perfect example of a certain quality or idea\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "pseudonym", 
        "question": "A fake name used by an author, a pen name\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "serialized", 
        "question": "Presented in parts; presented in a sequence\n"
    }
],
        "Lesson 11": [
    {
        "answer": "arboretum", 
        "question": "A park where trees and shrubs are displayed and studied\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "aviary", 
        "question": "A large cage or building for holding birds\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "botany", 
        "question": "The scientific study of plants\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "chameleon", 
        "question": "A type of lizard that changes color\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "cultivate", 
        "question": "a.  To grow crops; to prepare soil for growing crops\\nb.  To encourage the development of a friendship or an interest\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "habitat", 
        "question": "The environment a plant or an animal normally lives in\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "nurture", 
        "question": "To help to grow and develop; to take care of\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "talon", 
        "question": "The claw of a bird of prey, such as a hawk or an eagle\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "terrarium", 
        "question": "A clear container housing plants and small land animals\\n"
    }, 
    {
        "answer": "zoology", 
        "question": "The scientific study of animals\\n"
    }
],
        "Unit 4 Stems": [{"answer": "shape", "question": "Stem: morph\n\nExamples: amorphous, morphology, polymorphously, mesopmorph, protomorphic\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "clothes", "question": "Stem: vest\n\nExamples: vestry, vestment, vestibule, investiture, divest, divesture\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "good", "question": "Stem: bene\n\nExamples: benefit, benevolent, beneficial, benediction, benefactor, benign\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "weight", "question": "Stem: pond\n\nExamples: ponderous, ponder, preponderant, pound, imponderable, compound\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "body", "question": "Stem: corp\n\nExamples: corpulent, corporation, corporeal, corporal, corpse, corpuscle\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "sleep", "question": "Stem: dorm\n\nExamples: dormitory, dormant, dormer, dormancy, dormitive, dormient\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "father", "question": "Stem: pater\n\nExamples: paternalistic, patronize, paternity, patriarch, expatriate, paterfamilias\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "new", "question": "Stem: nov\n\nExamples: novel, nova, novice, novitiate, Nova Scotia, innovation, renovate\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "point", "question": "Stem: punct\n\nExamples: punctuate, punctilious, puncture, punctual, acupuncture, contapuntal\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "throw", "question": "Stem: ject\n\nExamples: eject, reject, conjecture, dejected, inject, subject, projection, interject\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "opinion", "question": "Stem: dox\n\nExamples: orthodox, heterodox, doxology, indoctrinate, paradox\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "Act or state", "question": "Stem: tion\n\nExamples: completion, reaction, devastation, production, creation, transition\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "place", "question": "Stem: loco\n\nExamples: locomotive, location, local, locus, relocate, dislocate, localize, locomotor\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "both", "question": "Stem: amphi\n\nExamples: amphibious, amphitheater, amphibian, amphigory, amphibolous\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "great", "question": "Stem: magn\n\nExamples: Magna Carta, magnanimous, magnate, magnificent, magnum opus\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "good", "question": "Stem: eu\n\nExamples: Eucharist, euphony, eulogy, euphemism, eugenics, euglena\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "within", "question": "Stem: endo\n\nExamples: endoplasm, endocrine, endogamous, endoskeleton, endothermic\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "fear", "question": "Stem: phobia\n\nExamples: claustrophobia, acrophobia, xenophobia, agoraphobia, hydrophobia\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "straight", "question": "Stem: ortho\n\nExamples: orthopedics, orthodontis, orthodox, orthography, orthogonal\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "think", "question": "Stem: put\n\nExamples: reputation, putative, impute, dispute, computer, disreputable\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "true", "question": "Stem: ver\n\nExamples: verify, veracity, veritable, verdict, verisimilitude, aver, cinema verite\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "mother", "question": "Stem: matri\n\nExamples: matricide, matron, matriarch, matrimony, matrilineal\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "large", "question": "Stem: mega\n\nExamples: megalith, megaphone, megalomania, megalopolis, megahertz, megaton\n\nOrigin: Greek\n"}, {"answer": "people", "question": "Stem: pop\n\nExamples: popular, populist, populate, population, popularize, populous\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}, {"answer": "blood", "question": "Stem: sangui\n\nExamples: sanguinary, sanguine, consanguinity, sangfroid, sangria\n\nOrigin: Latin\n"}],
"Lesson Ten":
[{"answer": "aesthetic",
"question": "a.  A standard of artistic beauty\nb.  Referring to artistic beauty or the appreciation of good taste"},
{"answer": "artisan",
"question": "A craftsperson; a skilled manual laborer"},
{"answer": "audition",
"question": "A tryout; a short performance given to try out for a part in a show"},
{"answer": "ceramics",
"question": "Objects made from clay or other combinations of minerals baked at high temperature"},
{"answer": "encore",
"question": "An additional performance demanded by an audience immediately after a program"},
{"answer": "medley",
"question": "A group of excerpts from musical pieces blended together into one longer number"},
{"answer": "mural",
"question": "A large image on a wall or ceiling"},
{"answer": "ornate",
"question": "Heavily and often excessively decorated"},
{"answer": "palette",
"question": "a.  A thin board on which an artist mixes paint of different colors\nb.  The range of colors used in a painting or by an artist"},
{"answer": "pantomime",
"question": "a. Acting that uses gestures and facial expression without speech\nb.  To express without speaking"}
],
"Lesson Nine":
[{"answer": "aspire",
"question": "To have great ambition or desire; to strive for"},
{"answer": "covet",
"question": "a.  To strongly desire something belonging to another\nb.  To long for, to crave"},
{"answer": "envy",
"question": "a.  A feeling of jealousy\nb.  To feel jealous"},
{"answer": "inclination",
"question": "a.  A preference; a tendency to act in a certain way\nb.  A slant or a leaning"},
{"answer": "persevere",
"question": "		To continue trying despite difficulties"},
{"answer": "reluctant",
"question": "		Unwilling; not want to do something"},
{"answer": "tantalize",
"question": "		To tempt but deny satisfaction"},
{"answer": "wary",
"question": "watchful and cautious"},
{"answer": "willful",
"question": "		Stubbornly determined to do what one wants"},
{"answer": "wistful",
"question": "Full of sad wishing or longing"}
],
        "Unit 3 Stems":
        [{"question": "homo\nExamples:homogenize, homonym, homophone, homologous, homozygous",
          "answer": "same"},
         {"question": "spec\nExamples:spectacles, specter, specious, spectrum, respect, inspect, prospectus",
          "answer": "look"},
         {"question": "duct\nExamples:conduct, ductile, induct, product, reduction, deduction, reproduction",
          "answer": "lead"},
         {"question": "fer\nExamples:transfer, infer, refer, defer, conifer, aquifer, auriferous",
          "answer": "carry"},
         {"question": "pend\nExamples:pending, pendulum, pendant, impending, depend, pendulous, suspend",
          "answer": "hang"},
         {"question": "micro\nExamples:micron, microscope, microwave, microphone, microcosm microbiotic, microorganism",
          "answer": "small"},
         {"question": "hydro\nExamples:hydroplane, hydroponics, dehydrate, hydrant, hydrogen, hydrophobia",
          "answer": "water"},
         {"question": "photo\nExamples:photograph, photometer, photon, photogenic, photosynthesis",
          "answer": "light"},
         {"question": "pan\nExamples:panorama, panoply, pandemic, pantheism, pantheon, Pan-American",
          "answer": "all"},
         {"question": "penta\nExamples:pentagram, pentagon, pentameter, pentathlon, pentarchy, pentahedron",
          "answer": "five"},
         {"question": "tele\nExamples:telescope, telephone, telepathy, telekinesis, teleology",
          "answer": "far"},
         {"question": "vid\nExamples:video, invidious, evidence, provide, videogenic, vide",
          "answer": "look"},
         {"question": "omni\nExamples:omnifarious, omnipotent, omnivorous, omniscient, omnibus, omnipresent",
          "answer": "all"},
         {"question": "ex\nExamples:exit, except, excise, exculpate, elucidate, exorbitant, eccentric, enumerate",
          "answer": "out"},
         {"question": "poly\nExamples:polyphony, polygyny, polygon, polygamy",
          "answer": "many"},
         {"question": "re\nExamples:return, review, retouch, reiterate, retail, revive, regenerate, regurgitate",
          "answer": "again"},
         {"question": "hypo\nExamples:hypodermic, hypocrite, hypotenuse, hypothermia, hypothesis",
          "answer": "under"},
         {"question": "pseudo\nExamples:pseudonym, pseudopod, pseudomorphic, pseudoscience, pseudoevent",
          "answer": "false"},
         {"question": "neuro\nExamples:neuron, neurosurgeon, neurosis, neurology, neurotomy",
          "answer": "nerve"},
         {"question": "tomy\nExamples:tonsillectomy, appendectomy, nerurotomy, dichotomy, anatomy, lobotomy",
          "answer": "cut"},
         {"question": "hema\nExamples:hematic, hematite, hematology, hematoma, hemal ",
          "answer": "blood"},
         {"question": "proto\nExamples:protoplasm, prototype, protozoa, proton, protohuman, protomorphic",
          "answer": "first"},
         {"question": "phon\nExamples:symphony, telephone, phonetic, phonograph, euphony, cacophony",
          "answer": "sound"},
         {"question": "mono\nExamples:monotonous, monomania, monocular, monogamous, monolithic, monotone",
          "answer": "one"},
         {"question": "viv\nExamples:vivid, vivacious, convivial, viva, revive, bon vivant",
          "answer": "life"}],
        "Lesson Eight Vocabulary":
        [{"answer": "bliss",
          "question": "Extreme joy, leading to contentment"},
         {"answer": "compassion",
          "question": "The feeling of sharing the suffering of another"},
         {"answer": "dismay",
          "question": "a.  To discourage; to upset\nb.  A sudden loss of courage or confidence, due to danger"},
         {"answer": "ecstatic",
          "question": "Overwhelmingly joyful; intensely delighted"},
         {"answer": "endear",
          "question": "To inspire friendly, affectionate feelings; to cause to be liked"},
         {"answer": "exasperate",
          "question": "To annoy greatly; to aggravate or irritate; to anger"},
         {"answer": "forlorn",
          "question": "Lonely; abandoned; sad"},
         {"answer": "somber",
          "question": "Dark; gloomy"},
         {"answer": "sullen",
          "question": "Bad tempered in a quiet, gloomy way; sulky"},
         {"answer": "wretched,",
          "question": "Miserable; dreadful"}
        ],
        "Lesson Seven Vocabulary":
        [{"answer": "abstain",
          "question": "a.  To not do something by choice\nb.  To not vote"},
         {"answer": "acknowledge",
          "question": "a.  To admit the truth, existence, or reality of something\nb.  To show you have received something"},
         {"answer": "advocate",
          "question": "a.  To recommend; to write or speak in favor of a cause\nb.  A person who argues for a cause"},
         {"answer": "coalition",
          "question": "An alliance of people, parties, or nations"},
         {"answer": "conform",
          "question": "To follow rules or customs"},
         {"answer": "invalid",
          "question": "Not effective or legal"},
         {"answer": "justify",
          "question": "To demonstrate that something is right or fair; to defend with reasons"},
         {"answer": "sanction",
          "question": "a.  To permit or approve of an action\nb.  To punish a nation or group that has broken accepted laws"},
         {"answer": "underlie",
          "question": "a.  To provide a basis of support\nb. To lie under"},
         {"answer": "uphold",
          "question": "To maintain or support in the face of possible opposition"}
        ],
        "Lesson Six Vocabulary":
        [{"answer": "contemplate",
          "question": "To consider carefully and thoughtfully"},
         {"answer": "	conviction",
          "question": "a.  A very strong belief or opinion\nb.  Being found guilty"},
         {"answer": "disseminate",
          "question": "To make widely known; to spread"},
         {"answer": "engross",
          "question": "To occupy the mind completely; absorb"},
         {"answer": "intuition",
          "question": "A feeling; a sense; understanding gained without thinking"},
         {"answer": "lucid",
          "question": "Easily understood; clear"},
         {"answer": "moral",
          "question": "a.  Conforming to a standard or right or good behavior\nb.  The lesson taught by a story, a fable, or an event"},
         {"answer": "profound",
          "question": "Deep; deeply thought or reasoned"},
         {"answer": "puritanical",
          "question": "Strict in matters of religious or moral conduct"},
         {"answer": "sanctify",
          "question": "To make holy or sacred"}
        ],
        "Lesson Five Vocabulary":
        [{"answer": "amelioration",
          "question": "The act of making better or improving"},
         {"answer": "assuage",
          "question": "To relieve or make less difficult"},
         {"answer": "compensate",
          "question": "a.  To pay\nb.  To make up for"},
         {"answer": "conserve",
          "question": "To protect from wasteful loss"},
         {"answer": "constructive",
          "question": "Serving a helpful and positive purpose"},
         {"answer": "enhance",
          "question": "To make better or more valuable"},
         {"answer": "enrichment",
          "question": "The act of making something richer or better; improvement"},
         {"answer": "neutralize",
          "question": "To cancel an effect or render it harmless"},
         {"answer": "preservation",
          "question": "The act of keeping something in good health or condition"},
         {"answer": "redeem",
          "question": "a.  To recover or buy back\nb.  To restore honor, worth, or value"}
        ],
        "Unit Two Stems":
        [{"question": "archy\nExamples: monarchy, oligarchy, hierarchy, anarchy, matriarchal, patriarch\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "government"},
         {"question": "ard\nExamples: drunkard, coward, braggart, dullard, sluggard\nOrigin: Germanic",
          "answer": "always"},
         {"question": "cide\nExamples: herbicide, homicide, matricide, suicide, genocide\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "kill"},
         {"question": "ician\nExamples: technician, musician, beautician, physician, statistician, clinician\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "specialist"},
         {"question": "itis\nExamples: appendicitis, tonsillitis, arthritis, gastroenteritis\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "inflammation"},
         {"question": "aqua\nExamples: aquarium, aquatic, aqueduct, aquifer, semiaquatic\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "water"},
         {"question": "audi\nExamples: audiophile, audience, audition, auditory, audiometer, audit, audiology\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "hear"},
         {"question": "bell\nExamples: belligerent, rebel, counter-rebellion\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "war"},
         {"question": "cap\nExamples: capture, captive, captor, captivate, captivity, caption, capsule\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "take"},
         {"question": "cise\nExamples: excise, incisors, incision, circumcise, incisive, precise, concise, decision\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "cut"},
         {"question": "bio\nExamples: biography, biology, biochemistry\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "life"},
         {"question": "auto\nExamples: autobiography, automobile, autography, automatic, automation, automaton, autocracy\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "self"},
         {"question": "port\nExamples: transport, import, report, porter, deport, important, portage, portly\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "carry"},
         {"question": "scrib\nExamples: scribble, inscribe, scribe, describe, conscription, transcribe, ascribe\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "write"},
         {"question": "logy\nExamples: biology, anthropology, geology, entomology, mythology\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "science"},
         {"question": "dict\nExamples: dictionary, predict, malediction, dictation, addict, contradict\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "say"},
         {"question": "cred\nExamples: credit, incredible, credible, incredulous, discredited, credibility, credo\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "believe"},
         {"question": "cent\nExamples: century, bicentennial, centimeter, centipede, centurion\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "one hundred"},
         {"question": "neo\nExamples: neologism, neon, Neolithic, neoclassic, neonatal, neophyte\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "new"},
         {"question": "ad\nExamples: adhesive, adapt, addendum, addition, adherent, addict, advent, advocate\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "to"},
         {"question": "cede\nExamples: recede, precede, antecedent, proceed, seceded, concede, intercede, succeed\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "go"},
         {"question": "miss\nExamples: dismiss, remiss, missile, admission, missionary, emission, promissory\nOrigin: Latin",
          "answer": "send"},
         {"question": "centri\nExamples: centrifugal, centrist, concentric, decentralize, eccentric\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "center"},
         {"question": "biblio\nExamples: bibliography, bibliophile, bible, bibliomania, bibliophobia, bibliolatry\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "book"},
         {"question": "anthropo\nExamples: anthropology, anthropoid, misanthrope\nOrigin: Greek",
          "answer": "man"}],
        "Vocabulary Lesson 4": 
        [
            {"answer": "allure",
             "question": "a.  A strong fascination or attraction; the power to attract\nb.  To attract with something desirable; entice"},
            {"answer": "avid",
             "question": "Eager; very enthusiastic"},
            {"answer": "devotion",
             "question": "Complete dedication to a cause or person"},
            {"answer": "effusive",
             "question": "Unrestrained or excessive in emotional expression; gushing"},
            {"answer": "exhilaration",
             "question": "Excited happiness"},
            {"answer": "fanatic",
             "question": "A person excessively and unreasonable devoted to a cause or belief"},
            {"answer": "indifferent",
             "question": "a.  Not interested in or concerned about something; not caring\nb.  Not good or bad; mediocre"},
            {"answer": "jubilant",
             "question": "Filled with joy"},
            {"answer": "reticent",
             "question": "a.  Unwilling; reluctant\nb.  Private about one’s affairs; tending to say little"},
            {"answer": "zealous",
             "question": "Highly motivated by dedication to a cause, an ideal, or a goal"}
        ],
        "Vocabulary Lesson 3":
        [
            {"answer": "brusque",
             "question": "Rough and short in manner or speech; abrupt; curt"},
            {"answer": "cordial",
             "question": "Warm and friendly"},
            {"answer": "dignity",
             "question": "a.  A calm manner indicating self-respect and worthiness\nb.  A sense of self-respect"},
            {"answer": "hospitable",
             "question": "Open and welcoming to guests"},
            {"answer": "irksome",
             "question": "Annoying; irritating"},
            {"answer": "nicety",
             "question": "a.  A small, often unimportant detail; a fine point\nb. An elegant detail or distinction; a refined feature or custom"},
            {"answer": "propriety",
             "question": "The quality of being proper; appropriateness"},
            {"answer": "refined",
             "question": "Very polite and cultured"},
            {"answer": "suave",
             "question": "Sophisticated; smoothly agreeable and polite"},
            {"answer": "tact",
             "question": "The ability to speak or act without offending others"}
        ],
        "Unit One Stems": [
            {"question": "ante\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:antedate, antecedent, antebellum, anterior, ante meridiem\n",
             "answer": "before"},
            {"question": "anti\nO{rigin: Greek\nExamples:antibody, anticlimax, anticline, antitoxin, antithesis anti-aircraft\n",
             "answer": "against"},
            {"question": "bi\nOrig{in: Latin\nExamples:bilateral, bicycle, binary, bimonthly, biped, bipolar, binocular, bicuspid\n",
             "answer": "two"},
            {"question": "circum\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:circumnavigate, circumspect, circumvent, circus\n",
             "answer": "around"},
            {"question": "com\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:combination, comfort, commensurate, common, complete, combo\n",
             "answer": "together"},
            {"question": "con\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:contract, confidence, confine, confederate, conjunction, contact\n",
             "answer": "together"},
            {"question": "de\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:deposit, descent, despicable, denounce, deduct, demolish, decrepit, deplete\n",
             "answer": "down"},
            {"question": "dis\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:distract, distort, dispute, dissonant, disperse, dismiss, dissuade, disprove\n",
             "answer": "away"},
            {"question": "equi\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:equitable, equilateral, equivocate, equinox, equation, equilibrium\n",
             "answer": "equal"},
            {"question": "extra\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:extraterrestrial, extraordinary, extravagant, extrovert, extramural\n",
             "answer": "beyond"},
            {"question": "inter\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:international, interdepartmental, interstellar, interject, interlude\n",
             "answer": "between"},
            {"question": "intra\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:intracellular, intravenous, intracranial, intrastate\n",
             "answer": "within"},
            {"question": "intro\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:introduce, introspective, introvert, introject, intromission\n",
             "answer": "into"},
            {"question": "mal\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:malevolent, malcontent, malicious, malign, malady, malapropism, malonym\n",
             "answer": "bad"},
            {"question": "mis\nOrigin: Germanic\nExamples:misfit, mistake, misfortune, misfire, misdeed, misguided\n",
             "answer": "bad"},
            {"question": "non\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:nonstop, nonprofit, nonconformity, nonplussed, nonchalant\n",
             "answer": "not"},
            {"question": "post\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:postgraduate, posthumous, postscript, posterity, posterior, postlude\n",
             "answer": "after"},
            {"question": "pre\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:prelude, preposition, premonition, premature, predict, predecessor\n",
             "answer": "before"},
            {"question": "semi\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:semitone, semiaquatic, semicircle, semiweekly, semiannual, semiformal\n",
             "answer": "half"},
            {"question": "sub\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:subterranean, subtract, subordinate, submarine, subterfuge, substantial\n",
             "answer": "under"},
            {"question": "super\nOrigin: Latin\nExamples:supervise, superb, superior, superfluous, supercilious, supernatural\n",
             "answer": "over"},
            {"question": "sym\nOrigin: Greek\nExamples:sympathy, symbiosis, symbol, symmetry, symphony, symposium\n",
             "answer": "together"},
            {"question": "syn\nOrigin: Greek\nExamples:synthetic, synchronize, syndrome, synonym, synopsis, syntax\n",
             "answer": "together"},
            {"question": "tri\nOrigin: Greek\nExamples:tricycle, triangle, triceps, triad, trichotomy, triceratops, trivia, trialogue\n",
             "answer": "three"},
            {"question": "un\nOrigin: Old English\nExamples:unfit, unequal, undone, unequivocal, unearned, unconventional, untenable\n",
             "answer": "not"}
        ],
        "Vocabulary Lesson 1":
        [
{"question": "Shortened, usually in reference to a written or spoken word.",
"answer": "abridged"},
{"answer": "browse",
"question": "a.  To look over reading material, sampling different parts\nb.  To look at in a leisurely and casual manner"},
{"answer": "citation",
"question": "a.  A reference to or a quotation from an authority\nb.  An official award for honorable behavior\nc.  An official order stating that one must appear in court"},
{"answer": "compendium",
"question": "a.  A short but complete written summary\nb.  A collection that includes a variety of written works"},
{"answer": "entry",
"question": "a.  In a reference book, a subject or word and information about it \nb.  The means or place by which to come in"},
{"answer": "etymology",
"question": "The origin and history of a word"},
{"answer": "gazetteer",
"question": "A dictionary of geographical places, including names and information"},
{"answer": "homonym",
"question": "A word having the same pronunciation as another word but a different meaning form that word"},
{"answer": "lexicon",
"question": "a.  A dictionary\nb.  The vocabulary of a particular subject or group"},
{"answer": "phonetics",
"question": "The study of the sounds of a language"}
        ],
        "Vocabulary Lesson 2":
[
{"answer": "clarify",
"question": "To make clear or understandable"},
{"answer": "confide",
"question": "To trust someone with private or secret information"},
{"answer": "disclose",
"question": "To reveal or to open to view"},
{"answer": "enlighten",
"question": "To inform or give new insight"},
{"answer": "exhibit",
"question": "a.  To show or arrange for public display\nb.  A display"},
{"answer": "expound",
"question": "To explain in detail or talk at length about a particular topic"},
{"answer": "ingrained",
"question": "Deep-seated; firmly imprinted or fixed"},
{"answer": "misconception",
"question": "A mistaken idea"},
{"answer": "sage",
"question": "a.  Wise; showing great wisdom\nb.  A person respected for experience and wisdom"},
{"answer": "seminar",
"question": "A class or a conference held to discuss ideas on a topic."
}
]
    };
